<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="dynamicfield-database">
    <title>The Dynamic Field <emphasis>Database</emphasis></title>

    <para>
        This feature implements a dynamic field of the type
<emphasis>Database</emphasis>.
    </para>

    <section>
        <title>Descrição</title>
        <para>
            Este recurso implementa um tipo de campo dinâmico genérico, que oferece a
possibilidade de recolher dados a partir do banco de dados externos. Tais
conjuntos de dados conectados pode ser pesquisado e filtrado utilizando
máscaras adicionais.
        </para>
        <para>
            encontrado e marcado o conjunto de dados relacionados, podem ser salvas para
o ticket particular através do campo dinâmico.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Database</emphasis> dynamic fields can be created the same way, as
the default dynamic fields are created.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Configuração</title>
        <para>
            A seguinte lista de opções de configuração podem ser utilizadas para este
recurso.
        </para>
        <section>
            <title>Adding a <emphasis>Database</emphasis> Dynamic Field</title>
            <para>
                This feature implements a configuration interface to create dynamic fields
of the type <emphasis>Database</emphasis>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Database</emphasis> dynamic fields can be created the same way, as
the default dynamic fields are created. For this switch to the
<emphasis>Admin → Ticket Settings → Dynamic Fields</emphasis> view. In this
mask you can select the <emphasis>Database</emphasis> field from the ticket
drop down box on the left side. Currently it's not possible to use the
<emphasis>Database</emphasis> dynamic field in the article context.
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Configuration <emphasis>General - Name</emphasis>:
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        Dynamic fields of the type <emphasis>Database</emphasis> need a unique name
just like other dynamic fields, too. This name has to contain only
alphanumeric values. This name will be used for internal handling of the
field but will not be displayed.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Configuration <emphasis>General - Label</emphasis>:
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        A etiqueta pode ser definida individualmente e pode conter espaços em branco
etc. Ele será utilizado como etiqueta do campo nas diferentes visualizações.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Configuration <emphasis>General - Field order</emphasis>:
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        A ordem do campo permite que um administrador altere a ordem do campo
dinâmico criado. Se mudar esta configuração obterá a ordem do campo geral
que será ajustada e outros campos dinâmicos serão removidos para uma posição
de volta.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Configuration <emphasis>General - Valid</emphasis>:
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        To use the dynamic field in the configured OTRS views it has to be set as
valid. If the field is set to <emphasis>invalid</emphasis> it will disappear
from all the configured views but no data will be lost.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Configuração externa da fonte de dados</title>
            <para>
                Antes um banco de dados externo pode ser pesquisado os resultados que serão
salvos no ticket, através de um campo dinâmico, as credenciais devem ser
armazenadas na configuração do campo dinâmico.  <figure>
                    <title>Dynamic Field Database Admin screen</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/dynamicfield-database/AdminOverview.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                Tipo: O tipo de banco de dados desejado pode ser selecionado aqui. O campo
suporta o padrão OTRS de tipos de banco de dados:MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL
ou MSSQL.
            </para>

            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>SID</emphasis>: This option is only available for Oracle
connections and will be shown or hidden automatically.  Within this option
you have to enter the SID of your Oracle connection.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Driver</emphasis>: This option is only available for ODBC
connections and will be shown or hidden automatically.  Within this option
you have to enter in the hostsystem previously configured ODBC driver to
connect to the desired MSSQL database.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Server</emphasis>: The database host (hostname or IP-Address).
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Port</emphasis>: The port of the database server.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Database</emphasis>: Defines the desired target database of the
DBMS. This database will be used for queries.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Table / View</emphasis>: This table or view will be used for the
queries.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>User</emphasis>: The username for the database connection.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Password</emphasis>: The user password for the database
connection.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Identifier</emphasis>: This select box will be automatically
filled through <emphasis>Possible Values (description
below)</emphasis>. This field represents the value which will be stored in
the dynamic field.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Multiselect</emphasis>: If this field is selected, it will be
possible to store more than one value to the dynamic field.  Those values
will be stored comma separated.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>CacheTTL</emphasis>: This value defines the period of validity of
the database cache in seconds. Equal queries to the database will be
answered through the cache (local filesystem) within this period instead of
asking the database again.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Searchprefix</emphasis>: This value will be put in the front of
every search term while using the autocompletion to search the
database. Wildcard characters are supported as well. The searchprefix will
be ignored during the detailed search, but it is still possible to use
wildcard characters in those masks.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Searchsuffix</emphasis>: This value will be put in the end of
every search term while using the autocompletion to search the
database. Wildcard characters are supported as well. The searchsuffix will
be ignored during the detailed search, but it is still possible to use
wildcard characters in those masks.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Result Limit</emphasis>: The entered integer value defines the
maximum amount of allowed results during a database search. This includes
the autocompletion search as well as the detailed search.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Case Sensitive</emphasis>: If this field is selected,
case-sensitivity will take effect on searches.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Possible values</emphasis>: As already explained the possible
values will fill up the identifier field automatically, which defines the
value that will be stored in the dynamic field. Possible values can be
created as much as needed (or at least as many table columns as the database
table has). The possible values defines the database columns to search
in. It is possible to set the column name, a description (label) the field
should have, the needed data type and if the field should be a search- or
listfield.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Name</emphasis>: The exact name of the database column which will
be requested through the database queries.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Description</emphasis>: The label of the field which will be
displayed in the detailed search.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Datatype</emphasis>: The data type which will be stored in the
dynamic field. Possible values: TEXT, INTEGER or DATE.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Filter</emphasis>: With the filter field, it is possible to choose
a ticket attribute or a dynamic field as a filter for the related column. If
the dynamic field is bound to a related ticket, the attributes will be used
for the filter mechanism, otherwise the filters will be ignored.  If filter
will be configured to a table column, only search results matching to the
search term and the related ticket attribute on exactly the configured
column will be displayed.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Searchfield</emphasis>: Indicates if a field should be included in
the search requests.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Listfield</emphasis>: Indicates if a field should be displayed in
the results.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Configuração da tela</title>
            <para>
                Dynamic fields of type <emphasis>Database</emphasis> have to be activated
for the several masks in which they should be displayed like the other types
of dynamic fields.
            </para>
            <para>
                This can be done through <emphasis>Admin → System Administration →
SysConfig</emphasis>, in which <emphasis>Ticket</emphasis> must be selected
on the left hand side.
            </para>
            <para>
                For every interface area (Frontend), in which the dynamic field of type
<emphasis>Database</emphasis> should be displayed, the admin has to
configure it to fit his needs. Examples:
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <literal>Frontend::Agent::Ticket::ViewZoom</literal> for the ticket zoom
view.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <literal>Frontend::Agent::Ticket::ViewPhoneNew</literal> for new phone
tickets.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <literal>Frontend::Agent::Ticket::ViewEmailNew</literal> for new email
tickets.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            In each of these view configurations is an entry called
<literal>Ticket::Frontend::AgentTicket*###DynamicField</literal>.  This
configuration defines which dynamic field(s) should get displayed in this
view. To add a dynamic field, the internal name of the field has to be
filled in the <emphasis>Key</emphasis> field. The field
<emphasis>Value</emphasis> can take the values 0 (deactivated), 1 (active)
and 2 (active and mandatory).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Armazenamento de dados históricos</title>
            <para>
                This feature offers a functionality to store historical data. For this to
work it´s necessary to activate and set SysConfig options, as visibly in the
following screenshot: <figure>
                    <title>Banco de dados DynamicField - Configuração de dados históricos</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/dynamicfield-database/SysConfigStoreHistoricalData.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                In the configuration option for the <literal>SourceDynamicField</literal>
it´s needed to fill in the already created dynamic (Database) field name,
which will be used to gather the historical data. In the related option
<literal>TargetDynamicField</literal> the field(s) <emphasis>Key</emphasis>
have to be filled with the table columns of the connected external database,
which will be readout.  For every column the related target dynamic field
has to be configured in the field <emphasis>content</emphasis>. The gathered
data will be saved in these dynamic fields.
            </para>
            <para>
                If the configuration is ready and active, the configured fields will be
readout from the external database, since the source field gets a new value
via the configured masks. The data will be searched by it´s stored
identifier via an event module and the found values will be stored in the
target dynamic fields.
            </para>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Configurações Sysconfig</title>

            <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                    <term><literal>AutoComplete::Agent###DynamicFieldDatabaseSearch</literal></term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Group: <literal>Framework</literal>, Subgroup:
<literal>Frontend::Agent</literal></para>
                        <para>
                            Define as opções de configuração para o recurso de preenchimento automático.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                    <term><literal>Ticket::EventModulePost###950-StoreHistoricalData</literal></term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Group: <literal>Ticket</literal>, Subgroup: <literal>Core::Ticket</literal></para>
                        <para>
                            Atualizações de campos dinâmicos, se os configurados serão atualizados.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                    <term><literal>DynamicFieldDatabase::StoreHistoricalData###1-SourceDynamicField1</literal></term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Group: <literal>OTRSBusiness</literal>, Subgroup: <literal>Core</literal></para>
                        <para>
                            Define a fonte no campo dinâmico para o armazenamento de dados históricos.
                        </para>
                        </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                    <term><literal>DynamicFieldDatabase::StoreHistoricalData###2-TargetDynamicFields1</literal></term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Group: <literal>OTRSBusiness</literal>, Subgroup: <literal>Core</literal></para>
                        <para>
                            Define o alvo do campo dinâmico para o armazenamento dos dados históricos.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                    <term><literal>DynamicFieldDatabase::StoreHistoricalData###3-SourceDynamicField2</literal></term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Group: <literal>OTRSBusiness</literal>, Subgroup: <literal>Core</literal></para>
                        <para>
                            Define a fonte no campo dinâmico para o armazenamento de dados históricos.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                    <term><literal>DynamicFieldDatabase::StoreHistoricalData###4-TargetDynamicFields2</literal></term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Group: <literal>OTRSBusiness</literal>, Subgroup: <literal>Core</literal></para>
                        <para>
                            Define o alvo do campo dinâmico para o armazenamento dos dados históricos.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
        </section>
    </section>




    <!-- ******** -->
<!-- 3. Usage -->
<!-- ******** -->
<section>
        <title>Aplicação</title>
        <para>
            utilizar um exemplar do seguinte  banco de dados DynamicField:
        </para>

        <section>
            <title>Pesquisando e salvando os conjuntos de dados - Preenchimento automático</title>
            <para>
                After the created dynamic fields are activated in the well known masks (like
<literal>ViewPhoneNew</literal>, <literal>ViewEmailNew</literal>) a new text
field appears with the name, the dynamic field got in the configuration.  In
this field it is possible to input searchterms and therefore execute a
search over all configured database fields.  Otherwise do a click on the
link <emphasis>Detailed search</emphasis> and start a detailed search in
which the fields to search in are selected explicitly.  <figure>
                    <title>Banco de dados DynamicField - campo de teste</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/dynamicfield-database/SearchFieldEmpty.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                Desde os termos de pesquisa são digitados no campo do texto, uma pesquisa no
banco de dados será iniciada e configurado as colunas  durante o resultado
será exibido através de um preenchimento automático do campo do texto abaixo
. O mais exato termo de pesquisa e mais exato será o resultado (menos
resultado de entradas).  <figure>
                    <title>DynamicField Database - Autocomplete feature</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/dynamicfield-database/SearchFieldAutoCompletion.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                Se o desejado valor será exibido nos resultados, pode ser selecionada
através de um clique com o mouse ou através do teclado e por conseguinte ser
adicionado os resultados nos campos dinâmicos.  <figure>
                    <title>Banco de dados DynamicField - Itens selecionados</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/dynamicfield-database/SearchFieldSelected.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                Via the link <emphasis>Details</emphasis> a popup screen can be accessed,
which offers detailed information about the whole result row.  This
information includes the line headers and the data. This information can be
used to get an overview about the rest (of the not configured) columns or to
compare data.
            </para>
            <para>
                Adicionado o resultado, o mesmo pode ser removido através do botão de
entrada menos.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Pesquisando e salvando os conjuntos de dados - Pesquisa detalhada</title>
            <para>
                The link <emphasis>Detailed search</emphasis> opens a new modal dialog to
start a new database search. In this mask it is possible to select the
fields to search on explicitly.  <figure>
                    <title>Banco de dados do DynamicField - Pesquisa detalhada</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/dynamicfield-database/DetailedSearchMask.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                By default the first available field is activated, but it´s also possible to
remove available fields or add additional ones. Only activated and filled
fields are considered for the search. Wildcard characters '*' are allowed in
every single field.
            </para>
            <para>
                The database search will be executed via the <emphasis>Start
search</emphasis> button and the results will be tabular displayed.  If the
search was successful, the results will be listed and one of the entries can
be selected via a mouse click. The value will be added to the list of saved
values afterwards.  <figure>
                    <title>Banco de dados do DynamicField - Resultado da pesquisa detalhada</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/dynamicfield-database/DetailedSearchResult.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                Utilizando independente o preenchimento automático ou a pesquisa detalhada,
pode apenas  cada resultado selecionado. Se um agente tentar selecionar um
valor várias vezes, uma mensagem de aviso será exibida.
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>







<!-- ********************************** -->
<!-- 4. Technical Implementation Detail -->
<!-- ********************************** -->
<!-- for internal use, don't generate
    <chapter>
        <title>Technical Implementation Details</title>
        <para>
            File: Kernel/Modules/AdminDynamicFieldDatabase.pm
            Modification: The module file for the administration interface of the dynamic field.
        </para>
        <para>
            File: Kernel/Modules/AgentDynamicFieldDatabaseDetailedSearch.pm
            Modification: The module file for the detailed search.
        </para>
        <para>
            File: Kernel/Modules/AgentDynamicFieldDatabaseSearch.pm
            Modification: The module file for the AJAX-Requests of the autocompletion.
        </para>
        <para>
            File: Kernel/Output/HTML/Standard/AdminDynamicFieldDatabase.tt
            Modification: The template file for the administration interface of the dynamic field.
        </para>
        <para>
            File: Kernel/Output/HTML/Standard/AgentDynamicFieldDatabaseDetailedSearch.tt
            Modification: The template file for the detailed search.
        </para>
        <para>
            File: Kernel/System/DynamicField/Driver/BaseDatabase.pm
            Modification: The driver module for the dynamic field.
        </para>
        <para>
            File: Kernel/System/DynamicField/Driver/Database.pm
            Modification: The main module of the dynamic field.
        </para>
        <para>
            File: Kernel/System/Database.pm
            Modification: The backend module for the database queries.
        </para>
        <para>
            File: var/httpd/htdocs/js/Core.Agent.Admin.DynamicFieldDatabase.js
            Modification: Specific JavaScript for the dynamic fields.
        </para>
        <para>
            File: var/httpd/htdocs/js/Core.Agent.DynamicFieldDatabaseSearch.js
            Modification: Specific JavaScript for the search queries and their processing.
        </para>
        <para>
            File: var/httpd/htdocs/skins/Agent/default/css/DynamicFieldDatabase.css
            Modification: Design modifications for the search result illustration.
        </para>
    </chapter>
    -->
</section>
