<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="dynamicfield-contact-with-data">
    <title>The Dynamic Field <emphasis>Contact with Data</emphasis></title>

    <para>
        Esse recurso permite adicionar os dados dos tickets com os contados.
    </para>

    <section>
        <title>Descrição</title>
        <section>
            <title>Definição dos dados e das fontes</title>
            <para>
                The data sources for this feature reside on the Dynamic Fields of the new
<emphasis>Contact with data</emphasis> type, this mean that each dynamic
field of this type is a new data source. The name of the dynamic field will
become the name of the data source, as they are both the same.
            </para>
            <para>
                For each data source (dynamic field) a list of contact attributes can be
defined (each attribute can contain only one text based value). The contact
attributes can be set as mandatory and searchable if needed. The sort order
of the attributes can be also defined.
            </para>
            <para>
                Os atributos de contato para cada origem de dados podem conter qualquer
informação sobre o contato, conforme o necessário, tais como endereços
diferentes, telefone, aniversário, comida favorita, hobbies, etc.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    The attributes <literal>Name</literal> and <literal>ValidID</literal> are
always mandatory and they are not automatically added, so for each new data
source these attributes must be added manually.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Within the data source definition (or dynamic field configuration) they must
be represented by the keys <literal>Name</literal> and
<literal>ValidID</literal> respectively while the values could be
<emphasis>Name</emphasis> and <emphasis>Validity</emphasis> for example.
                </para>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Gerenciamento de contato</title>
            <para>
                Depois de ter, pelo menos uma fonte de dados ( Contato com dados do campo
dinâmico) definindo, informações dos contatos que podem ser adicionados à
fonte para preenche-la.
            </para>
            <para>
                Apart from the <literal>Name</literal> and <literal>ValidID</literal>, each
data source could contain different contact information as defined by the
data source (e.g. a data source could have an E-mail field while another
could contain Telephone and/or Mobile fields).
            </para>
            <para>
                The management (adding or updating) contact for the data sources is done by
an special screen that can be called from the Ticket menu (<emphasis>Edit
contacts with data</emphasis>) in the main navigation bar.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Adicionando os contatos dos tickets</title>
            <para>
                Para cada contato com os dados configurados no campo dinâmico, um contato é
criado especialmente para este campo dinâmico (ou fonte de dados) podem ser
escolhidas a partir de qualquer ticket ou criar ticket de tela de ação onde
a dinâmica foi arquivada na e configurada anteriormente.
            </para>
            <para>
                Os atributos do contato serão mostrados na tela de zoom do ticket.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Uso de pesquisa em contatos e estatísticas</title>
            <para>
                Tickets can be found in search and statistics via the required attribute
<literal>Name</literal>.
            </para>
            <para>
                The <literal>Name</literal> can also be returned as a field value.
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Configuração</title>

        <variablelist>
            <title>Configuração do Sistema</title>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><literal>AdminContactWithData::RunInitialWildcardSearch</literal></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Group: <literal>OTRSBusiness</literal>, Subgroup:
<literal>Frontend::Admin::AdminContactWithData</literal></para>
                    <para>
                        Define se uma pesquisa deve ser executada quando o marcador inicialmente
chamar o gerenciamento de contatos.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><literal>Frontend::Module###AdminContactWithData</literal></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Group: <literal>OTRSBusiness</literal>, Subgroup:
<literal>Frontend::Agent::ModuleRegistration</literal></para>
                    <para>
                        Permite atribuir contato e as permissões  de gerenciamento de detalhas de
contato através da definição do grupo.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Aplicação</title>
        <para>
            Em uma aplicação exemplar de contatos com os seguintes dados:
        </para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Create a new dynamic field of type <emphasis>Contact with data</emphasis>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Set the possible contact attributes (possible
values). <literal>Name</literal> and <literal>ValidID</literal> are required
for any Contact with data Dynamic Field.
                </para>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Add <literal>Name</literal> attribute (Key: <literal>Name</literal>, Value:
<emphasis>Name</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Add <literal>ValidID</literal> attribute (Key: <literal>ValidID</literal>,
Value: <emphasis>Validity</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Add any other attribute such as <literal>Telephone</literal> attribute (Key:
<literal>Telephone</literal>, Value: <emphasis>Phone</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the list of mandatory attribute keys comma separated
(<literal>Name</literal> and <literal>ValidID</literal> are not needed).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Set the attribute key order list comma separated as:
<literal>Name,Telephone,ValidID</literal>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the list of searchable attribute keys comma separated
(<literal>Name</literal> is not needed).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Populate the data source by adding at least one contact in the newly created
data source by using <emphasis>Tickets → Edit contacts with data</emphasis>
screen from the main navigation bar.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the new dynamic field to the screen's configuration where it should be
shown. For example in <emphasis>New Phone Ticket</emphasis> screen by
updating the system configuration setting:
<literal>Ticket::Frontend::AgentTicketPhone###DynamicField</literal> and do
the same for
<literal>Ticket::Frontend::AgentTicketZoom###DynamicField</literal>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Go to <emphasis>New phone ticket</emphasis> screen, and notice that the new
field is there.  Add all ticket needed information.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Selecione um contato existente usando o preenchimento automático e
escolhendo um contato.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    O contato e seus atributos serão mostrados no zoom da tela do ticket.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    It is possible to update the attributes of the contact by clicking the
<emphasis>Edit contact data</emphasis> button that appears in the right side
of the title of the contact data box (if the current user is a member of the
groups defined in system configuration setting
<literal>Frontend::Module###AdminDynamicFieldContactWithData</literal>).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Se for necessário alterar o contato para este ticket, isso pode ser feito
através de qualquer outra ação do ticket onde o campo dinâmico estiver
configurado para exibir.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>



<!-- for internal use, don't generate
    <chapter>
        <title>Technical Implementation Details</title>
        <para>
            Via a new DynamicField admin module the configuration of contacts will be managed and stored in the DynamicField configuration.
        </para>
        <para>
            The configured contact are read from the DynamicField configuration via an admin module and changes are stored there as well.
        </para>
        <para>
            Within the ticket only the internal contact id as well as the content of the field 'Name' will be stored.
        </para>

        <para>
            Autocomplete functionality for setting the contact and display of contact attributes is provided by an output filter in order to prevent changes to framework files.
        </para>
    </chapter>
    -->
</section>
