<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="sms-notifications-and-notification-web-view">
    <title>Notificação do SMS e Notificação da visualização da web</title>

    <section>
        <title>Descrição</title>
        <para>
            The <emphasis role="bold">OTRS Business Solution</emphasis>™ comes with two
new notification features: SMS notifications and the notification web
view. Both of them are technically notification methods besides the existing
email method and can be activated for each notification (e.g. "Ticket new
note notification" or "Ticket create notification") on the
AdminNotificationEvent screen.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Configurando as notificações do SMS</title>
        <note>
            <para>
                Before taking advantage of SMS notification transport method, you must first
<link linkend="sms-cloud-service-activate">activate the SMS cloud
service</link>.
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            In order to use SMS as a way of notification for admins and customers, you
have to buy an SMS unit package.  Please get in touch with sales@otrs.com on
this matter. Once you've bought a package, you will be able to look up your
current contingent of remaining SMS units on the admin screen for the SMS
cloud service (AdminCloudServiceSMS).
        </para>
        <para>
            To make SMS available for notifications, you have to enable it for the
notifications of your choice in AdminNotificationEvent. Besides the existing
"Email" notification method, you can enable SMS notifications by enabling
the checkbox as to be seen in the screenshot below.
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                Please be careful using the "Send by default" checkbox on SMS
notifications. Enabling this checkbox will cause this notification to be
sent by SMS to all agents with a phone number stored in the configured
field. This could cause a high usage of your available SMS units!
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            On this screen, you can also add more generic phone numbers (e.g. for
archiving purposes) which will receive all of the relevant notifications
(besides the addressed agents). Please note that all of these recipients
will be treated as customers (regarding article creation.).
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Ativando as notificações do SMS</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/notifications/sms-notification-transport.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
        <para>
            Se você tiver configurado uma notificação para ser visível nas preferencias
do agente, os agentes deverão agora ser capazes de ativar/desativar as
notificações no SMS manualmente no seu próprio para esta notificação.
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Configurações da notificação das preferências do agente SMS</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/notifications/sms-notification-agent-preferences.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
        <para>
            SMS notification text will be constructed on fly by combining both Subject
and Text fields of the corresponding language. You can of course use
supported OTRS tags in these fields, and additionally URLs can be shortened
by activating URL shortening option in cloud service configuration.
        </para>
        <figure>
            <title>SMS Notification Text Fields</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/notifications/sms-notification-text.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Configurando e utilizando a visualização da notificação da web</title>
        <para>
            Configurando as notificações visualizada na web para agentes, é semelhante a
configuração de notificações SMS conforme descrito acima.
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Visualizando e ativando as notificações da web</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/notifications/NotificationWebView.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
        <para>
            Uma vez que você ativar a notificação para uma determinada notificação na
web view, visualizarão um novo ícone na parte superior da tela OTRS (dentro
da barra de ferramenta) cada vez que chaga uma nova notificação.
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Visualizar as notificação da web no ícone na barra de ferramentas</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/notifications/NotificationWebViewNew.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
        <para>
            Clicando neste ícone, os agentes deverão obter uma visão geral de todas as
suas notificações e pode ler e descartá-los aqui.
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Visualizar as notificação fora  da web</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/notifications/NotificationWebViewOverview.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Visualizar os detalhes da notificação da web</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/notifications/NotificationWebViewDetail.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
    </section>
</section>
