<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="resource-planning">
    <title>Resource Planning</title>

    <section>
        <title>Descrição</title>
        <para>
            Resource planning feature in OTRS Business Solution™ complements built-in
calendar feature of OTRS. It enhances original calendar implementation by
introducing resource allocation for appointments. Furthermore, resources can
be assigned to separate teams, which in turn can be used to filter resource
overview and availability.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Configuração</title>
        <para>
            Nenhuma configuração adicional necessária.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Aplicação</title>
        <section>
            <title>Team Management</title>
            <para>
                In order to be able to assign appointments to resources, you must first
define teams for those resources.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Team Management Add and Import</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/resource-allocation/TeamManagementAddImport.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                Teams can be added or imported from Manage Teams screen accessible via top
navigation menu. In order to import a team, you must have an exported YML
configuration file of the team from an existing OTRS installation.
            </para>
            <para>
                Adding new team is easy: just define a team name and permission group. Full
access to this group is required for anyone to be able to manage the team,
its agents and assign them as resources to appointments.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Team Management Add and Import</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/resource-allocation/TeamManagementEdit.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Team Agent Management</title>
            <para>
                Once you have teams set up, you must define which agents belong to which
teams. This is done via dedicated screen where you can adjust relations of
agents and teams very much like you can do it for agents and groups.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    Please note that in order to see agents in this screen, you must define them
first via Admin &gt; Agents screen.
                </para>
            </note>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Team Agent Management</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/resource-allocation/TeamManagementAgents.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                By choosing a team from this screen, you can assign agents to it, and
vice-versa.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Team Agent Relations</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/resource-allocation/TeamManagementAgentRelations.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Assigning Appointments to Resources</title>
            <para>
                Finally, once you have both teams and their agents set up, you can proceed
to a calendar overview and start assigning appointments to teams and agents.
            </para>
            <para>
                Simply add or edit an appointment, and choose both team and agent from the
lists under resource. You can do this via any calendar overview, as
appointment edit dialog is the same for all of them.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Assigning team and agent to an appointment</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/resource-allocation/AppointmentEditResource.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                You can assign multiple teams and agents to a single appointment, but you
must always choose a team first. Resulting list of agents is an aggregate of
all selected teams, without any duplicates. Choosing an agent from the list
is also optional, so you can leave an appointment assigned only to a team.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Assigning multiple teams and agents to an appointment</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/resource-allocation/AppointmentEditResourceMultiple.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    Once you assign an appointment to a team and/or agent, make sure to save it
so your changes are applied.
                </para>
            </note>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Resource Overview</title>
            <para>
                While it's possible to assign resources to an appointment in any calendar
overview, one screen is designed exclusively for allocating resources to
appointments: Resource Overview. This screen looks very much like a regular
calendar overview, except it has a filter for teams on top and a list of
agents for that team (available only in timeline views).
            </para>
            <para>
                By choosing a team from the top filter, you will be presented with all
appointments assigned to it.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Resource Overview</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/resource-allocation/ResourceOverview.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                By simply dragging an appointment to a row line with an agent's name in
timeline view, it's possible to assign an appointment to this resource. If
an appointment does not have an agent assigned to it, it will appear in the
unassigned area of the screen.
            </para>
            <para>
                Appointment with multiple agents will be displayed as duplicated, but it
most certainly is not. Dragging one instance of this appointment will move
all them in the same fashion.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Resource Overview</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/resource-allocation/ResourceOverviewMultiple.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    Please note that appointments with unassigned teams or assigned different
team than currently selected, will not show up in the resource overview. You
will have to switch to a different overview to see these appointments, so
make sure to assign them to a correct team first.
                </para>
            </note>
            <para>
                By editing settings of the resource overview (via gear icon in top right
corner), you can choose which team agents are displayed within the overview.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Resource Overview Settings</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/resource-allocation/ResourceOverviewSettings.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                This setting is user and team specific, and if you have defined an agent
filter in this way, a trash icon will be displayed on top of the list of
agents so you can remove it easily.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Resource Overview Filter Delete</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/resource-allocation/ResourceOverviewFilterDelete.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                In all other aspects, resource overview screen behaves in the same way as a
regular calendar overview.
            </para>
        </section>

    </section>

</section>
