<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="chat">
    <title>Chat</title>

    <section>
        <title>Description</title>
        <para>
            The chat feature of <emphasis role="bold">OTRS Business Solution</emphasis>™ allows for chats between agents and customers using the OTRS frontend. Once enabled, customers (or public users) can start chats with agents and vice versa. Finished chats can be archived and attached to tickets.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Configuration</title>
        <para>
            The following configuration options are relevant for this feature. Please note that you can also define a list of fixed texts which are being displayed to public users and customers in the chat module. For more information on which texts can be changed, please have a look at the module configuration (OTRSBusiness &gt; Core::Chat).
        </para>
        <section>
            <title><literal>ChatEngine::Active</literal></title>
            <para>Group: OTRSBusiness, Subgroup: Core::Chat</para>
            <para>
                Controls whether or not the chat feature is enabled.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title><literal>ChatEngine::ChatDirection::PublicToAgent</literal></title>
            <para> Group: OTRSBusiness, Subgroup: Core::Chat</para>
            <para>
                Controls whether or not public users should be able to start chats (please note that the frontend module configuration for the public chat frontend in <literal>PublicFrontend::Module###PublicChat</literal> has to be enabled, too).
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title><literal>ChatEngine::ChatDirection::CustomerToAgent</literal></title>
            <para> Group: OTRSBusiness, Subgroup: Core::Chat</para>
            <para>
                Controls whether or not customers should be able to start chats (please note that the frontend module configuration for the customer chat frontend in <literal>CustomerFrontend::Module###CustomerChat</literal> has to be enabled, too).
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title><literal>ChatEngine::ChatDirection::AgentToCustomer</literal></title>
            <para> Group: OTRSBusiness, Subgroup: Core::Chat</para>
            <para>
                Controls whether or not agents should be able to start chats with customers directly.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title><literal>ChatEngine::ChatDirection::AgentToAgent</literal></title>
            <para> Group: OTRSBusiness, Subgroup: Core::Chat</para>
            <para>
                Controls whether or not agents should be able chat with eachother.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title><literal>ChatEngine::PermissionGroup::ChatReceivingAgents, ChatEngine::PermissionGroup::ChatNotificationAgents, ChatEngine::PermissionGroup::ChatStartingAgents</literal></title>
            <para> Group: OTRSBusiness, Subgroup: Core::Chat</para>
            <para>
                Defines groups for the certain features. Receiving: Groups which can receive and accept chat requests. Notification: Groups which do receive notifications about new/pending chat requests. Starting: Groups which are allowed to start new chats at all.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title><literal>ChatEngine::DefaultAgentName</literal></title>
            <para> Group: OTRSBusiness, Subgroup: Core::Chat</para>
            <para>
                A default name which should be displayed to customers and public users instead of the real name of the chatting agents. If empty or disabled, the real agent name will be shown.
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Usage</title>
        <section>
            <title>The chat manager</title>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
                    <screeninfo>The chat managing screen</screeninfo>
                    <graphic srccredit="Chat manager - screenshot" scale="160" fileref="screenshots/chat/ChatManager.jpeg"></graphic>
                </screenshot>                
            </para>
            <para>
                The chat manager is the central point of the chat feature. As an agent, here you can manage your chats, see and accept open requests and change your chat availability status. The chat manager provides a list of chat requests from customers, public users and other agents, as well as an overview over all active chats. Open the chat manager by using "Chat" in the main navigation of OTRS.
            </para>
            <para>
                You can set your general availability for the chat by using the checkbox in the left sidebar of the chat manager. Once disabled, you'll no longer get notified for incoming chat requests.
            </para>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Using the chat widget</title>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
                    <screeninfo>The chat widget</screeninfo>
                    <graphic srccredit="Chat widget - screenshot" scale="80" fileref="screenshots/chat/ChatWidget.png"></graphic>
                </screenshot>                
            </para>
            <para>
                To send messages, you can use the text field in the chat widget in your list of active chats. Once you are done with typing your message, submit it by either clicking the send icon next to the text field, or using tab and enter (consecutively). When the message has been sent, the cursor will jump back to the text field to allow for easily continuing to type.
            </para>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Starting new chats and dealing with chat requests</title>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
                    <screeninfo>Start a chat</screeninfo>
                    <graphic srccredit="Chat start - screenshot" scale="70" fileref="screenshots/chat/ChatStartWidget.png"></graphic>
                </screenshot>                
            </para>
            <para>
                As an agent, there are multiple ways to start a chat. First of all, you can use the user online widget on the dashboard to chat with agents or customers who are currently logged in to OTRS. Just click the little chat icon behind the name of the agent or customer. A small overlay will appear and allow for entering the first chat message you would like to send to the other user. Afterwards, the new chat is being added to the chat manager.
            </para>
            <para>
                You can also use ticket zoom to start a chat with a certain customer. In the sidebar, you'll find a chat link in the customer information widget.
            </para>
            <para>
                If new chat requests arrive and you're logged in to OTRS, you'll get notified by a chat icon in the toolbar on top of the screen. The icon also holds information about how many open chat requests are available at the moment. Just click the icon to open the chat manager. You'll also receive a browser notification (popup) in case of new chat requests.
            </para>
            <para>
                All agents with the needed permissions will be able to deal with open chat requests. A request can only be accepted by one agent at the same time, which means that the request will disappear from the other agents lists once if has been accepted by an agent. Once accepted, the newly created chat will be appended to the list of active chats for the agent who has accepted it. Other users in the chat will see a notification about the user who just entered the chat.
            </para>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Ending and archiving chats</title>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
                    <screeninfo>The chat actions</screeninfo>
                    <graphic srccredit="Chat actions - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/chat/ChatIcons.png"></graphic>
                </screenshot>                
            </para>
            <para>
                As an agent, you have several possiblities to end a chat. First of all, you can just discard a chat by using the "x" icon on the right top side of the chat widget in the chat manager. The chat then just will be closed without archiving it. Other users in the chat will just see a message telling them the chat was ended.
            </para>
            <para>
                You can also append the chat to an existing ticket. Click the "+" icon on the right top of the chat widget in the chat manager. A new window will open which allows for selecting a ticket which the chat should be appended to.
            </para>
            <para>
                If you don't have any appropriate ticket to append the chat to, you can also create a new one by using the phone icon on the top right side of the chat widget in the chat manager.
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>

</section>
