<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="dynamicfield-contact-with-data">
    <title>The Dynamic Field "Contact with Data"</title>

    <para>
        This feature allows to add contacts with data to tickets.
    </para>

    <section>
        <title>Description</title>
        <section>
            <title>Definition of data sources</title>
            <para>
                The data sources for this feature reside on the Dynamic Fields of the new 'Contact
                with data' type, this mean that each Dynamic Field of this type is a new data
                source. The name of the dynamic field will become the name of the data source, as
                they are both the same.
            </para>
            <para>
                For each data source (Dynamic Field) a list of contact attributes can be defined
                (each attribute can contain only one text based value). The contact attributes can
                be set as mandatory and searchable if needed. The sort order of the attributes can
                be also defined.
            </para>
            <para>
                Contact attributes for each data source could contain any information about the
                contact as needed, such as different addresses, telephone, birthday, anniversaries,
                favorite food, hobbies, etc.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    The attributes 'Name' and 'ValidID' are always mandatory and they are not
                    automatically added, so for each new data source these attributes must be added
                    manually.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Within the data source definition (or Dynamic Field configuration) they must be
                    represented by the keys 'Name' and 'ValidID' respectively while the values could
                    be 'Name' and 'Validity' for example.
                </para>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Contact management</title>
            <para>
                After having at least one data source (Contact with data Dynamic Field) defined,
                contacts information can be added to the source to populate it.
            </para>
            <para>
                Apart from the 'Name' and the 'ValidID', each data source could contain different
                contact information as defined by the data source (e.g. a data source could have an
                E-mail field while another could contain Telephone and/or Mobile fields).
            </para>
            <para>
                The management (adding or updating) contact for the data sources is done by an
                special screen that can be called form the Ticket menu (Edit contacts with data) in
                the main navigation bar.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Adding contacts to tickets</title>
            <para>
                For each configured contact with data dynamic field, a contact created specifically
                for this dynamic  field (or data source) can be chosen from any ticket create or
                ticket action screen where the dynamic filed has been previously configured.
            </para>
            <para>
                The contact attributes will be shown in the ticket zoom screen.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Usage of contacts in search and statistics</title>
            <para>
                Tickets can be found in search and statistics via the required attribute 'Name'.
            </para>
            <para>
                The 'Name' can also be returned as a field value.
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Configuration</title>

        <variablelist>
            <title>SysConfig</title>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>AdminContactWithData::RunInitialWildcardSearch</term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Group: OTRSBusiness, Subgroup: Frontend::Admin::AdminContactWithData</para>
                    <para>
                        Defines if a search with placeholder should be executed when initially calling the contact management.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Frontend::Module###AdminContactWithData</term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Group: OTRSBusiness, Subgroup: Frontend::Agent::ModuleRegistration</para>
                    <para>
                        Allows to distribute contact and contact detail management permissions via group definition.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Usage</title>
        <para>
            An exemplary usage of contacts with data is as follows:
        </para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Create a new dynamic field of type 'Contact with data'.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Set the possible contact attributes (possible values). 'Name' and 'ValidID'
                    are required for any Contact with data Dynamic Field.
                </para>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Add 'Name' attribute (Key: Name, Value: 'Name').
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Add 'ValidID' attribute (Key: ValidID, Value: 'Validity').
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Add any other attribute such as 'Telephone' attribute (Key:
                            Telephone, Value: 'Phone').
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the list of mandatory attribute keys comma separated ('Name' and 'ValidID'
                    are not needed).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Set the attribute key order list comma separated as: Name,Telephone,ValidID.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the list of searchable attribute keys comma separated ('Name' is not
                    needed).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Populate the data source by adding at least one contact in the newly created
                    data source by using 'Tickets' -&gt; 'Edit contacts with data' screen from the
                    main navigation bar.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the new dynamic field to the screen's configuration where it should be
                    shown. For example in New Phone Ticket screen by updating the SysConfig
                    setting: Ticket::Frontend::AgentTicketPhone###DynamicField and do the same
                    for Ticket::Frontend::AgentTicketZoom###DynamicField.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Go to New phone ticket screen, and notice that the new field is there.
                    Add all ticket needed information.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Select an existing contact using autocomplete and choosing a contact.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    The assigned contact and its attributes will be shown in the ticket zoom
                    screen.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    It is possible to update the attributes of the contact by clicking the 'Edit
                    contact data' button that appears in the right side of the title of the
                    contact data box (if the current user is a member of the groups defined
                    in SysConfig setting Frontend::Module###AdminDynamicFieldContactWithData).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    If is necessary to change the contact for this ticket, it can be done via
                    any other ticket action where the dynamic field is configured for display.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <!-- for internal use, don't generate
    <chapter>
        <title>Technical Implementation Details</title>
        <para>
            Via a new DynamicField admin module the configuration of contacts will be managed and stored in the DynamicField configuration.
        </para>
        <para>
            The configured contact are read from the DynamicField configuration via an admin module and changes are stored there as well.
        </para>
        <para>
            Within the ticket only the internal contact id as well as the content of the field 'Name' will be stored.
        </para>
        <para>
            Autocomplete functionality for setting the contact and display of contact attributes is provided by an output filter in order to prevent changes to framework files.
        </para>
    </chapter>
    -->

</section>
