<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="dynamicfield-contact-with-data">
    <title>The Dynamic Field <emphasis>Contact with Data</emphasis></title>

    <para>
        Ez a funkció lehetővé teszi a partneradatok hozzáadását a jegyekhez.
    </para>

    <section>
        <title>Leírás</title>
        <section>
            <title>Adatforrások meghatározása</title>
            <para>
                The data sources for this feature reside on the Dynamic Fields of the new
<emphasis>Contact with data</emphasis> type, this mean that each dynamic
field of this type is a new data source. The name of the dynamic field will
become the name of the data source, as they are both the same.
            </para>
            <para>
                For each data source (dynamic field) a list of contact attributes can be
defined (each attribute can contain only one text based value). The contact
attributes can be set as mandatory and searchable if needed. The sort order
of the attributes can be also defined.
            </para>
            <para>
                A partner attribútumai az egyes adatforrásoknál szükség szerint bármilyen
információt tartalmazhatnak a partnerről, mint például különböző címek,
telefon, születésnap, évfordulók, kedvenc étel, szabadidős tevékenység, stb.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    The attributes <literal>Name</literal> and <literal>ValidID</literal> are
always mandatory and they are not automatically added, so for each new data
source these attributes must be added manually.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Within the data source definition (or dynamic field configuration) they must
be represented by the keys <literal>Name</literal> and
<literal>ValidID</literal> respectively while the values could be
<emphasis>Name</emphasis> and <emphasis>Validity</emphasis> for example.
                </para>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Partnerkezelés</title>
            <para>
                Miután rendelkezik legalább egy meghatározott adatforrással (partneradatok
dinamikus mező), a partnerek információi hozzáadhatók a forráshoz a
kitöltésükhöz.
            </para>
            <para>
                Apart from the <literal>Name</literal> and <literal>ValidID</literal>, each
data source could contain different contact information as defined by the
data source (e.g. a data source could have an E-mail field while another
could contain Telephone and/or Mobile fields).
            </para>
            <para>
                The management (adding or updating) contact for the data sources is done by
an special screen that can be called from the Ticket menu (<emphasis>Edit
contacts with data</emphasis>) in the main navigation bar.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Partnerek hozzáadása a jegyekhez</title>
            <para>
                Minden egyes beállított partneradatok dinamikus mezőnél a kifejezetten ehhez
a dinamikus mezőhöz (vagy adatforráshoz) létrehozott partner bármely olyan
jegylétrehozás vagy jegyművelet képernyőről kiválasztható, ahol a dinamikus
mező előzőleg be lett állítva.
            </para>
            <para>
                A partner attribútumai láthatóak lesznek a jegynagyítás képernyőn.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Partnerek használata a keresésben és a statisztikákban</title>
            <para>
                Tickets can be found in search and statistics via the required attribute
<literal>Name</literal>.
            </para>
            <para>
                The <literal>Name</literal> can also be returned as a field value.
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Beállítás</title>

        <variablelist>
            <title>Rendszerbeállítások</title>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><literal>AdminContactWithData::RunInitialWildcardSearch</literal></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Group: <literal>OTRSBusiness</literal>, Subgroup:
<literal>Frontend::Admin::AdminContactWithData</literal></para>
                    <para>
                        Meghatározza, hogy egy helykitöltővel rendelkező keresést végre kell-e
hajtani a partnerkezelés kezdeti meghívásakor.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><literal>Frontend::Module###AdminContactWithData</literal></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Group: <literal>OTRSBusiness</literal>, Subgroup:
<literal>Frontend::Agent::ModuleRegistration</literal></para>
                    <para>
                        Lehetővé tesz a partner és a partnerrészlet kezelési jogosultságok
felosztását csoportmeghatározáson keresztül.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Használat</title>
        <para>
            A partneradatok egy példaszerű használata a következőképpen lehet:
        </para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Create a new dynamic field of type <emphasis>Contact with data</emphasis>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Set the possible contact attributes (possible
values). <literal>Name</literal> and <literal>ValidID</literal> are required
for any Contact with data Dynamic Field.
                </para>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Add <literal>Name</literal> attribute (Key: <literal>Name</literal>, Value:
<emphasis>Name</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Add <literal>ValidID</literal> attribute (Key: <literal>ValidID</literal>,
Value: <emphasis>Validity</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Add any other attribute such as <literal>Telephone</literal> attribute (Key:
<literal>Telephone</literal>, Value: <emphasis>Phone</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the list of mandatory attribute keys comma separated
(<literal>Name</literal> and <literal>ValidID</literal> are not needed).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Set the attribute key order list comma separated as:
<literal>Name,Telephone,ValidID</literal>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the list of searchable attribute keys comma separated
(<literal>Name</literal> is not needed).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Populate the data source by adding at least one contact in the newly created
data source by using <emphasis>Tickets → Edit contacts with data</emphasis>
screen from the main navigation bar.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Add the new dynamic field to the screen's configuration where it should be
shown. For example in <emphasis>New Phone Ticket</emphasis> screen by
updating the system configuration setting:
<literal>Ticket::Frontend::AgentTicketPhone###DynamicField</literal> and do
the same for
<literal>Ticket::Frontend::AgentTicketZoom###DynamicField</literal>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Go to <emphasis>New phone ticket</emphasis> screen, and notice that the new
field is there.  Add all ticket needed information.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Jelöljön ki egy meglévő partnert az automatikus kiegészítés használatával,
és válasszon ki egy partnert.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    A hozzárendelt partner és annak attribútumai láthatóak lesznek a
jegynagyítás képernyőn.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    It is possible to update the attributes of the contact by clicking the
<emphasis>Edit contact data</emphasis> button that appears in the right side
of the title of the contact data box (if the current user is a member of the
groups defined in system configuration setting
<literal>Frontend::Module###AdminDynamicFieldContactWithData</literal>).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Ha a partner megváltoztatása szükséges ennél a jegynél, akkor az bármely
olyan egyéb jegyműveleten keresztül elvégezhető, ahol a dinamikus mező be
van állítva a megjelenítéshez.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>



<!-- for internal use, don't generate
    <chapter>
        <title>Technical Implementation Details</title>
        <para>
            Via a new DynamicField admin module the configuration of contacts will be managed and stored in the DynamicField configuration.
        </para>
        <para>
            The configured contact are read from the DynamicField configuration via an admin module and changes are stored there as well.
        </para>
        <para>
            Within the ticket only the internal contact id as well as the content of the field 'Name' will be stored.
        </para>

        <para>
            Autocomplete functionality for setting the contact and display of contact attributes is provided by an output filter in order to prevent changes to framework files.
        </para>
    </chapter>
    -->
</section>
