<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="sysconfig-history">
    <title>System Configuration History</title>
    <section>
        <title>Leírás</title>
        <para>
            This added functionality provides administrators with screens to go through
system configuration deployment and specific settings history, and make
changes if needed.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Beállítás</title>
        <para>
            További beállítás nem szükséges.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Használat</title>
        <section id="sysconfig-deployment-history">
            <title>Üzembe állítási előzmények</title>
            <para>
                To access deployment history, go to <emphasis>System Configuration →
Deployment</emphasis> screen and click on <emphasis>History</emphasis>
button. This screen will display recent deployments in a descending order,
along with their comments and name of the user who deployed the changes.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>System configuration deployment history</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/sysconfig-history/sysconfig-deployment-history.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                Every deployment can be further inspected by clicking on <emphasis>View
Details</emphasis> link next to it. <emphasis>Details</emphasis> screen can
be used to compare the setting with its previous value, before the
deployment took place.
            </para>
            <para>
                Additionally, older deployments (every one before current state) can be
restored with a simple click.  By restoring a deployment, all settings will
be reverted to the value they had at the time of the deployment in question.
            </para>
            <para>
                Finally, deployments can be exported with click on the export button. User
will be presented with a download of a YML file that contains changed
settings. This YML file can be later restored via <emphasis>Import &amp;
Export</emphasis> screen in the system configuration screen.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section id="sysconfig-setting-history">
            <title>Setting History</title>
            <para>
                Specific setting history can be accessed via <emphasis>History</emphasis>
button in the setting widget. This button opens a screen of all values
setting had over different deployments. Information like name of the user
that made the change and time of change is displayed, along with a useful
comparison tool.
            </para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>System configuration setting history</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/sysconfig-history/sysconfig-deployment-history.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
            </para>
            <para>
                Every historical setting value can be restored by clicking on the
<emphasis>Restore</emphasis> button in upper right corner.
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>
</section>
